Guide to the Collection of materials relating to Liberace
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Collection of materials relating to Liberace
1940-1990
GEN MSS 1528
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
3.5
(5 boxes) + 6 broadside
Contains photographs, printed material, scripts, posters, phonograph records, and ephemera relating to Liberace.
Content Description
This collection documents the American pianist, singer and actor, Liberace, largely between the 1950s and 1980s. Material includes photographs, printed material, scripts, posters, phonograph records, and ephemera relating to Liberace and his career.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Walter Reuben, 2012.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Box 5 (phonograph records): Restricted fragile material. Consult Access Services for further information.
Liberace
Władziu Valentino Liberace (1919-1987) was an American pianist, singer, and actor. Liberace was born in West Allis, Wisconsin on May 16, 1919. His father, Salvatore Liberace, was an immigrant from Italy. His mother, Frances Zuchowska, was Polish. From the 1950s to the 1970s, Liberace was the highest-paid entertainer in the world, noted for his signature performance style and elaborate costumes. In addition to his music career, Liberace also appeared in several television programs and films, including South Sea Sinner (1950), The Liberace Show (1952), and Sincerely Yours (1955). He died on February 4, 1987.
Arrangement
Collection is arranged roughly in the order received, with materials grouped together by format.
Pianists -- United States -- 20th Century; Actors -- United States -- 20th Century; Entertainers -- United States; Advertising -- Motion pictures -- Posters; Phonograph records; Audiovisual materials; Liberace, 1919-1987
- Photographs, circa 1940s-1970s; 3 folders (Box 1)
- Ephemera, circa 1960s-1980s (Box 2)
- Liberace: Complete Life Story periodical, 1954 (Box 2)
- Screenplay for South Sea Sinner, 1949 (Box 2)
- Screenplay for Liberace, 1988 (Box 2)
- Theatrical release and musical performance posters, 1953; 1960; 1965 (Folder 3 (Broadside))
- Theatrical release and musical performance posters, 1955; 1965 (Box 4 (Oversize))
- Photograph of Liberace and his mother, Frances, 1954 (Box 4 (Oversize))
- Periodicals and publicity material, 1950-1954 (Box 4 (Oversize))
- Lobby cards for Sincerely Yours, When the Boys Meet the Girls, and South Sea Sinner, 1950; 1955; 1965 (Box 4 (Oversize))
- Posters for Sincerely Yours, 1955; 5 folders (Folder 6 (Broadside)–7 (Broadside), Folder 8 (Broadside oversize), Folder 9 (Broadside)–10 (Broadside))
- Liberace phonograph records, 1952-1964 (Box 5)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  - Sincerely, Liberace, 1955; 4 phonograph records (Box 5)
  - It's Shadow Time/Velvet Moon, 1952; 1 phonograph record (Box 5)
  - As Time Goes By, 1960; 2 phonograph records (Box 5)
  - The Magic Pianos of Liberace and Gordon Robinson, 1960; 2 phonograph records (Box 5)
  - Rhapsody by Candelight, 1962; 2 phonograph records (Box 5)
  - My Inspiration, 1960; 2 phonograph records (Box 5)
  - Piano Song Book, 1959; 2 phonograph records (Box 5)
  - Liberace Plays Golden Themes from Hollywood, 1964; 1 phonograph record (Box 5)
  - Liberace at the London Palladium, 1961; 2 phonograph records (Box 5)
  - My Parade of Golden Favorites, 1961; 2 phonograph records (Box 5)
- Flabber Talking Doll, circa 1990s (Box 11)
  Biographical / Historical
  Flabber, who bears resemblance to Liberace, is a character from the American live-action television series, Big Bad Beetleborgs, which aired for two seasons on Fox Kids between September 7, 1996, and March 2, 1998.